what is empire Empire is the desire to
expand a sphere of influence Empire is a
desire to increased access to resources
access to expertise and manpower Empire
is expansive seeking to know more of the
world Empire on the darker side also
relies on other ring right we have a
right to take over territory and impose
our will on the world because our way is
a better way something like that and so
that notion of spreading a superior
culture feels like it's a part of empire
building Empire will imposition control
control of territory control of
resources reproduction of the ego in the
cosmos
Empire has no bounds the Imperial will
wants to conquer all waits for the next
weakness to be able to take over more
territory to absorb more energy the
emperor at the core spinning a web all
over the universe until it's control is
total so keywords they're conquering
control domination they're those kinds
of feelings
they essential to Empire is necessarily
a bundle is it necessarily power seeking
historically it definitely does seem to
be that way is it possible for some of
the things mentioned in the first bit so
you know expansion of horizons
increasing knowledge you know increasing
open reach around the world but not
necessarily in a malign way is it
possible is it is it is it an empire if
it is built collaboratively is not quite
the right word does Empire necessarily
involve subjugation conquering
oppression and so on Empire violence war
the expansion of the self to contain all
of being or the expansion of the ego to
contain all being possessing being the
benefit of the ego or possessing being
the benefit of the self self with a big
s being possessed by being for the
benefit of being the equality of the
inner and the outer or the devouring of
the outer for the benefit of the inner
feed feed the void at the core is more
and more territory more and more energy
so Empire is rooted in ego the egos
desire to impose itself on the world and
so yes so there's an arrogance then in
Empire right that that's
I am so good
I am so right that there's a
righteousness is there not in
empire-building it's not just or maybe
that's just a justification for the
greed and the violence because there's
that there's this it's theft as well
right you are the the territory that you
take over you are robbing the
inhabitants of that territory of their
way of life so there's a there's a
callousness alongside the arrogance
their ego Empire the ego devouring
hungry hungry never satiated spinning an
empire down the generations planting
dark seed so they continue to blossom
creating all of the inciting beauties of
empire with the resources I have stolen
with the territory which I believe I
deserve to inherit the kingdom of the
earth with this and make some beauty to
hypnotize the Emperor usually has some
kind of justification for being the
Emperor God's chosen one or something
like that right the Dragon Slayer
whatever it might be and so the myth of
the emperor is part of the building of
the empire either the the story
it's not just the violence the violence
the armies yes that's the initial
takeover but the maintenance of the
empire relies on buying into a narrative
about the empire now that must
necessarily be a false narrative because
the Empire is manifestation of the ego
out of control
the Emperor as a sick monarch a
corrupted monarch who knows not the
limits of their Kingdom doesn't know how
to respect different kingdoms that exist
thinks themselves more divine than they
actually are the emperor has no clothes
the emperor's robes of what distinguish
it distinguishes emperor from the others
their appearance their crown
this myth is one half of perpetuating
the Empire the other one is to
institutionalize fear
hungry ghosts so the Emperor is the
shadow of the king right the King
bestows blessing on his kingdom respects
the boundaries of adjacent kingdoms the
emperor is the tyrant form of the king
right lady there there the the willful
spreading of himself across the world
that the tyrant is underpinned by the
tyrant is the bipolar form of the
weakling and so the weakling is the true
nature of the Emperor because it is
rooted in ego because it is not aha
because the connection to the divine is
not actually embodied it's a it's a sham
the emperor is actually terrified the
fear of the core of the emperor and thus
the need to possess all of being too
tame being to prevent being from
devouring Emperor but the emperor
possesses or of being the Emperor thinks
if they can accumulate enough matter
then they will be able to block the void
at the core from something oh yes look
at me I continue down the generations
100 years 200 years a thousand years
2,000 years they still speak of me and
they forget that the void at the core is
infinite